Mss.Rec.258 Mss.Rec.258
American Philosophical Society
Study of Arapaho tonal phonology
1992
Mss.Rec.258
American Philosophical Society
27.0 Tape(s)
Linguistic field recordings of elicited Arapaho grammar, verbs, adjectives, adverbs, kinship terms, personal names, and general vocabulary. Also includes anecdotes and stories given in Arapaho and English from the consultant's childhood, and about her grandfather and late 19th-century Arapaho history in Oklahoma. Recorded in Watonga, Oklahoma.
27 sound cassettes (23 hr., 52 min.): analog, 1 7/8 ips, stereo.
Cleveland, Edna
Weigel, William F.
Conditions Governing Access
Restricted access. Requires permission of Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Presented by William Weigel in 1996 in form of audiocassette copies of original tapes prepared by the Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Location of Originals note
Orignal tapes held at the Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley.
Related Archival Materials
Researcher's project report, notes on tape duplication from Berkeley Language Center, and transcript from recording sessions available in the Phillips Fund Collection (Mss.497.3.Am4).
Arrangement note
The recordings held at the APS library are 27 60-minute cassettes that were copied from the collector's original 23 90-minute cassettes. Some of the collector's original tapes are not included on the copies held at the APS Library: tape 2, side B; tape 5, side B; tape 7, sides A and B; tape 15, side B.
General note
Contents of tapes 15 and 16 are identical.
Arapaho Indians--History; Arapaho language; Oklahoma--History--Land Rush, 1889; Sound recordings
- Audio recordings
  - Arapaho animal names & other nouns [1 of 2], 1992-06-15; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:42:27; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Scope and Contents note
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 1:1, collector's original tape 1, side A.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Audiocassette) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Animals--Nomenclature; Arapaho language; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Arapaho animal names & other nouns [2 of 2], 1992-06-15; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:06; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 1:2, collector's original tape 1, side B.
  - Body parts, general nouns, numbers, 1992-06-16; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:40:42; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 2:1, collector's original tape 2, side A. The subsequent program 2:2 was not copied on to tapes.
    Arapaho language; Arapaho language--Numerals; Human body--Terminology; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Arapaho kinship terms, 1992-06-17; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:35:16; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 3:1, collector's original tape 3, side A.
    Arapaho Indians--Kinship; Arapaho language; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Stories of Oklahoma Land Run, etc., in Arapaho with English paraphrase, 1992-06-17; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:26:10; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 3:2, collector's original tape 3, side B.
    Arapaho Indians--Social conditions; Arapaho language; Diseases--Terminology; Dust Bowl Era, 1931-1939; Oklahoma--History--Land Rush, 1889; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Arapaho elicitation, verb conjugations [1 of 2], 1992-06-19; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:42:21; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 4:1, collector's original tape 4, side A.
    Arapaho language; Arapaho language--Verbs; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Arapaho elicitation, verb conjugations [2 of 2], 1992-06-19; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:45; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 4:2, collector's original tape 4, side B.
  - English glossing session for Oklahoma Land Run story, 1992-06-22; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:30; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 5:1, collector's original tape 5, side A. The subsequent program 5:2 was not copied on to tapes.
    Arapaho language; Oklahoma--History--Land Rush, 1889; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Elicitation of Arapaho verb forms, 1992-06-22; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:35; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Arapaho language--Verbs; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Arapaho verbs, genetives, relative clauses [1 of 2], 1992-06-23; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:35:31; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 6:1, collector's original tape 6, side A.
    Arapaho language--Grammar; Arapaho language--Verbs; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Arapaho verbs, genetives, relative clauses [2 of 2], 1992-06-23; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:29; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 6:2, collector's original tape 6, side B. The subsequent original programs 7:1 and 7:2 were not copied on to tapes.
  - Arapaho proper names, greetings [1 of 2], 1992-06-25; 07-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:41:16; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 8:1, collector's original tape 8, side A.
    Arapaho Indians--Kinship; Arapaho language; Names, Arapaho; Salutations; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Arapaho proper names, greetings [2 of 2], 1992-06-25; 07-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:25:22; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 8:2, collector's original tape 8, side B.
    Arapaho language; Names, Arapaho; Salutations; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Arapaho adjectives, comparison, demonstration, adverbs [1 of 2], 1992-06-26; 08-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:37:39; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 9:1, collector's original tape 9, side A.
    Arapaho language--Adjectives; Arapaho language--Adverbs; Arapaho language--Grammar; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Arapaho adjectives, comparison, demonstration, adverbs [2 of 2], 1992-06-26; 08-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:26:41; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 9:2, collector's original tape 9, side B.
  - Sitting Bull story about finding a live scalped man in a pool of blood they mistook for water, 1992-06-30; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:21; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    The Sitting Bull referred to is the consultant's grandfather, unrelated to the Hunkpapa Lakota leader Sitting Bull. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 10:1, collector's original tape 10, side A.
    Arapaho Indians--History; Arapaho language; Battlefields; Scalping; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Arapaho words & phrases, and Social Dance story, 1992-06-30; 09-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:20; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 10:2, collector's original tape 10, side B.
    Arapaho dance; Arapaho Indians--Clothing & dress; Arapaho Indians--Music; Arapaho language; dress; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Sitting Bull story about seeing his future in badger entrails, 1992-06-30; 09-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:29; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Arapaho Indians--History; Arapaho Indians--Social life and customs; Arapaho language; Divination; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous Arapaho words and phrases, 1992-06-30; 09-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:27:29; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 10:1, collector's original tape 10, side A.
    Arapaho language; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Direct vs. indirect questions, conjuctions, verb forms [1 of 3], 1992-07-01; 10-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:37; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 11:1, collector's original tape 11, side A.
    Arapaho language; Arapaho language--Grammar; Arapaho language--Interrogative; Arapaho language--Verbs; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Direct vs. indirect questions, conjuctions, verb forms [2 of 3], 1992-07-01; 10-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:46; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 11:2, collector's original tape 11, side A.
  - Direct vs. indirect questions, conjuctions, verb forms [3 of 3], 1992-07-01; 11-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:27:22; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 11:3, collector's original tape 11, side B.
  - Direct vs. indirect questions [1 of 2], 1992-07-02; 11-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:40:36; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 12:1, collector's original tape 12, side A.
    Arapaho language; Arapaho language--Interrogative; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Direct vs. indirect questions [2 of 2], 1992-07-02; 12-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:39:50; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 12:2, collector's original tape 12, side B.
  - Arapaho stories [1 of 2], 1992-07-03; 12-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:37:51; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 13:1, collector's original tape 13, side A.
    Arapaho dance; Arapaho Indians--History; Arapaho Indians--Social life and customs; Arapaho language; Ghost dance; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Arapaho stories [2 of 2], 1992-07-03; 13-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:18; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 13:2, collector's original tape 13, side B.
    Arapaho Indians--History; Arapaho language; Miracles; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Elicited Arapaho phrases & sentences, 1992-07-06; 13-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:33:02; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 14:1, collector's original tape 14, side A.
  - Stories about Arapahoes in Wyoming and an incident with a dead body, 1992-07-06; 14-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:00; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Begins with discussion of Arapaho population in Oklahoma, followed by two stories, each given in Arapaho and English. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 14:2, collector's original tape 14, side B.
    Arapaho Indians--Oklahoma; Arapaho Indians--Wyoming; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Arapaho phrase elicitation, 1992-07-06; 14-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:17:40; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 14:3, collector's original tape 14, side B.
  - Conjunct conjugation of taa?awat, locatives, copula, comparison [1 of 2], 1992-07-07; 15-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:26:48; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 15:1, collector's original tape 15, side A.
    Arapaho language--Grammar; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Conjunct conjugation of taa?awat, locatives, copula, comparison [2 of 2], 1992-07-07; 15-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:18:49; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 15:2, collector's original tape 15, side A. The subsequent original programs 15:3 and 16:1 were not copied on to tapes.
  - Basic vocabulary, A-H [1 of 2], 1992-07-08; 17-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:06; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 16:2, collector's original tape 16, side A.
  - Basic vocabulary, A-H [2 of 2], 1992-07-08; 17-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:36:35; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 17:1, collector's original tape 16, side B.
  - Basic vocabulary, H-P [1 of 2], 1992-07-09; 18-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:44:30; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 18:1, collector's original tape 17, side A.
  - Basic vocabulary, H-P [2 of 2], 1992-07-09; 18-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:42; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 18:2, collector's original tape 17, side B.
  - Basic vocabulary, P-S [1 of 2], 1992-07-10; 19-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:41:33; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 19:1, collector's original tape 18, side A.
  - Basic vocabulary, P-S [2 of 2], 1992-07-10; 19-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:48; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 19:2, collector's original tape 18, side B.
  - Basic vocabulary, S-Z [1 of 3], 1992-07-13; 20-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:53; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 20:1, collector's original tape 19, side A.
  - Basic vocabulary, S-Z [2 of 3], 1992-07-13; 20-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:26:14; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 20:2, collector's original tape 19, side A.
  - Basic vocabulary, S-Z [3 of 3], 1992-07-13; 22-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:32:46; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 20:3, collector's original tape 19, side B.
  - Arapaho negative verb forms [2 of 3], 1992-07-14; 22-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:17:40; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 21:2, collector's original tape 20, side A.
  - Arapaho negative verb forms [1 of 3], 1992-07-14; 22-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:58; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 21:1, collector's original tape 20, side A.
  - Arapaho negative verb forms [3 of 3], 1992-07-14; 22-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:27:29; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 21:3, collector's original tape 20, side B.
  - Transcription & glossing session for Arapaho stories [1 of 9]: The Peach Tree, 1992-07-15; 23-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:21:46; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Transcription and glossing session of previously recorded Arapaho stories played back. This program contains the story "The Peach Tree." Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 22:1, collector's original tape 21, side A.
    Arapaho Indians--History; Arapaho language; Peach; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Transcription & glossing session for Arapaho stories [2 of 9]: The Peach Tree, 1992-07-15; 23-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:31; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Transcription and glossing session of previously recorded Arapaho stories played back. This program contains the story "The Peach Tree." Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 22:2, collector's original tape 21, side A.
  - Transcription & glossing session for Arapaho stories [3 of 9]: The Peach Tree, 1992-07-15; 24-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:43:27; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Transcription and glossing session of previously recorded Arapaho stories played back. This program contains the story "The Peach Tree." Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 23, collector's original tape 22, side B.
  - Transcription & glossing session for Arapaho stories [4 of 9]: The Peach Tree; How Sitting Bull Quit the Rain Dance, 1992-07-16; 24-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:10; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Transcription and glossing session of previously recorded Arapaho stories played back. This program contains the stories "The Peach Tree" and "How Sitting Bull Quit the Rain Dance." The Sitting Bull referred to is the consultant's grandfather, unrelated to the Hunkpapa Lakota leader Sitting Bull. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 24:1, collector's original tape 22, side A.
    Arapaho Indians--History; Arapaho language; Conversion--Christianity; Ghost dance; Peach; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Transcription & glossing session for Arapaho stories [5 of 9]: How Sitting Bull Quit the Rain Dance, 1992-07-16; 25-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:26:25; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Transcription and glossing session of previously recorded Arapaho stories played back. This program contains the story "How Sitting Bull Quit the Rain Dance." The Sitting Bull referred to is the consultant's grandfather, unrelated to the Hunkpapa Lakota leader Sitting Bull. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 24:2, collector's original tape 22, side A.
    Arapaho dance; Arapaho Indians--History; Arapaho Indians--Religion; Arapaho language; Ghost dance; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Transcription & glossing session for Arapaho stories [6 of 9]: How Sitting Bull Quit the Rain Dance, 1992-07-16; 25-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:42:34; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Transcription and glossing session of previously recorded Arapaho stories played back. This program contains the story "How Sitting Bull Quit the Rain Dance." The Sitting Bull referred to is the consultant's grandfather, unrelated to the Hunkpapa Lakota leader Sitting Bull. Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 25:1, collector's original tape 22, side B.
  - Transcription & glossing session for Arapaho stories [7 of 9]: The Death of James Blindy, 1992-07-17; 26-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:21:51; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Transcription and glossing session of previously recorded Arapaho stories played back. This program contains the story "The Death of James Blindy." Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 26:1, collector's original tape 23, side A.
    Arapaho Indians--History; Arapaho language; Oklahoma--History--Land Rush, 1889; Watonga (Okla.)
  - Transcription & glossing session for Arapaho stories [8 of 9]: The Death of James Blindy, 1992-07-17; 26-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:49; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Transcription and glossing session of previously recorded Arapaho stories played back. This program contains the story "The Death of James Blindy." Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 26:2, collector's original tape 23, side A.
  - Transcription & glossing session for Arapaho stories [9 of 9]: The Death of James Blindy, 1992-07-17; 27-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:27:46; Cleveland, Edna; Weigel, William F.
    Transcription and glossing session of previously recorded Arapaho stories played back. This program contains the story "The Death of James Blindy." Original tapes held at Berkeley Language Center, University of California, Berkeley. This program is a copy of the Language Center tape 26:3, collector's original tape 23, side B.